所以现在我们有请求流过我们的
so now that we have requests flowing through our
我们可以添加的管道
pipeline we can add
用于转换请求的专用功能
specialized functions to transform either the request
或回应
or the response
例如
for example
假设我们收到了削减野生动物的请求
let's say we get a request for slash wildlife
好吧，我们想以同样的方式处理
well we want to handle that the same way
我们会要求削减野生动物
we would a request for slash wild things
啊，我们可以添加一个重写的转换
ah we can add a transformation that rewrites
只有那些请求
only those requests
为此，我们需要在地图上进行模式匹配
and to do that we'll need to pattern match on maps
这是一种在长生不老药中广泛使用的技术
which is a technique that's used extensively in elixir
它也很强大
and it's also really powerful
我们首先在此处添加了对野生动物的新请求
we've started by adding a new request for wildlife here
现在如果你对所有这些感到不安
now if you're feeling uneasy about all these
请求是
requests being
复制并粘贴在文件底部
copied and pasted at the bottom of the file
好吧，现在就去吧
well just go with it for now
稍后
a bit later on
我们会将这些添加到自动化测试中
we'll add these to an automated test and
摆脱这一切
get rid of all this
重复代码
duplicated code
所以我们想要请求
so we want the request for
由这个函数类处理的野生动物
wildlife to be handled by this function class
为了做到这一点，我们需要改变
in order to do that we're going to need to change
野生动物的请求路径
the path of that request from wildlife
野生的东西
to wild things
所以它与功能爪相匹配
so it matches the function claws
我们需要改变那条路
and we're going to need to change that path
在路线发生之前
before the route happens
所以如果我们只看这里的管道
so if we just look at our pipeline up here
我们有 pars 日志然后 rout
we've got pars log and then rout
所以它显然需要在pars之后但在之前
so it needs to come after pars obviously but before
溃败，我实际上要把它放在前面
rout and I'm actually going to put it before
也登录，以便我们可以注销
log as well so that we can log out
最终结果
the final result
所以就在这里
so right here in the pipeline
我们将添加一个名为 rewrite path 的步骤
we're going to add a step called rewrite path
然后定义该功能
and then to define that function
是正确的道路
be right path
好吧，它需要一张对话地图和
well it needs to take a conversation map and
还返回一个对话地图
also return a conversation map
我们要做的就是更新
and all we want to do in here is update
给定的地图并将其路径更改为
the given map and change its path to
野生的东西
wild things
所以现在如果我们运行良好
so now if we run it well
我们看到它几乎重写了
we see that it pretty much rewrites
我们所有的要求
all of our requests
野生的东西
to wild things
我们只希望这个函数运行
we only want this function to run
如果地图以野生动物为路径
if the map has wildlife as the path
我们实际上可以使用模式匹配来做到这一点
and we can actually use pattern matching to do that
让我们玩一下模式匹配
let's play around with pattern matching
一秒钟的性爱地图
maps in sex for just a second
我在这里设置了一个对话地图
I've got a conversation map set up here
带有关键方法和关键路径
with a key method and a key path
我们想要做的是将它与地图进行模式匹配
and what we want to do is pattern match it to a map
有一条路径
that has a path of
削减野生动物
slash wildlife
我们使用匹配运算符
we use the match operator
像这样使用右侧的地图
use that map on the right hand side like that
它匹配
and it matches
即使左边的地图
even though the map on the left
没有与地图相同数量的键
doesn't have the same number of keys as the map
只要左边是地图就在右边
on the right as long as this left hand side is a map
它有一个以野生动物为值的路径键
and it has a path key with wildlife as the value
那么这匹配
then this matches
换句话说，我们不必提供
in other words we don't have to provide
成功匹配的所有键或值
all the keys or values for a successful match
这很棒
and this is great
因为我们只对匹配路径感兴趣
because we're only interested in matching the path
我们不在乎方法是什么
we don't care what the method is
现在假设我们改变
now let's say we change
这周围并设置了我们在这里使用熊的野生动物
this around and set a wildlife we use bears right here
好吧，那不会是一场比赛
well that's not going to be a match
因为路径键的值
because the value of the path key
在期限和权利
in the term and the right
不是熊它实际上是野生动物所以
is not bears it's actually wildlife so
我们得到了无与伦比的空气
we get a no match air
所以我们会把它放回野生动物
so we'll set it back to wildlife
然后如果我们有一个键名会发生什么
and then what happens if we have a key name
左手边有一个超值麦克风
with a value mic on this left hand side
好吧，这不是一场比赛，因为
well that's not a match because the
右侧的地图没有键名
map on the right hand side doesn't have a key name
和模式中的键
and the keys in the pattern
必须存在于右边的地图中
must exist in the map on the right
现在如果我们是
now if we were
只对获取请求感兴趣，我们可以做点什么
only interested in get requests we could do something
就像这个方法是get
like this method is get
这将与对话相匹配
and that will match the conversation
它会匹配
it will match
右侧任何具有获取方法的地图
any map on the right hand side that has a method of get
现在让我们假设我们要检查
now let's suppose we want to check
该路径与野生动物相匹配，如果匹配
that the path matches wildlife and if it does
然后也提取方法的值
then also extract the value of the method
所以不要在这里使用文字 git
so instead of using a literal git here
我们将只使用变量方法
we'll just use a variable method
然后 path 将使用真正的野生动物
and then path will use a literal wildlife
它匹配，现在
and it matches and now
方法的价值
the value of the method
绑定到该变量方法
is bound to that variable method
它是
it's
还值得注意的是，我们可以绑定多个变量
also worth noting that we can bind multiple variables
一气呵成
in one go
是的，我们只需绑定方法和
yeah we'll just bind method and
也是我们不关心文字字符串的路径
also the path we don't care about the literal string
我们只想
we just want to
将我们拥有的任何路径绑定到变量路径
bind whatever path we have to the variable path
我们也得到了
and we get that as well
所以这给了我们
so this gives us
完成函数子句所需的一切
everything we need to finish our function clause
是的，记住我们只是在这里有一个争论
yeah remember we just have an argument co nv here
但我们会匹配它
but we'll pattern match it
我们会说我们希望它成为一条路径
we'll say we want it to be a path
用字面的斜线野生动物
with the literal slash wildlife
然后我们可以在这里使用匹配运算符
and then we can use the match operator right here
所以这要做的是
so what this is going to do is
将传入的参数与此映射匹配
match the incoming argument against this map
并将其分配给变量 con
and also assign it to the variable co n
我们需要这样做，因为我们需要使用
and we need to do that because we need to use
函数体中的 co 和 v 在这里
co and v in the function body here
更新该对话地图并返回一个新的
to update that conversation map and return a new one
如果你不需要在函数体中使用它
if you didn't need to use it in the function body
好吧，你可以这样做
well you could just do it just like this
它会匹配即将到来的论点
and it would match the argument that's coming in
并且仅在匹配时运行此功能
and only run this function if that matches
但在我们的例子中，我们需要捕捉到
but in our case we need to capture that
所以我们可以这样做
so we can do that
所以让我们保存并运行它
so let's give that a save and run it
哦，我们在这里得到一个错误
ooh and we get an error here
它是说没有
it's saying that there's no
功能爪
function claws
那是
that's
匹配方法为 get 且路径为的地图
matching a map where the method is get and the path is
野生的东西
wild things
那是因为我们正在调用重写路径
well that's because we're calling rewrite path for
管道中的每个请求
every request in the pipeline
但是这里的功能爪
but the function claws here
只匹配
only matches
当参数是具有路径键的映射时
when the argument is a map with the path key of
野生动物不是野生动物
wildlife not wild things
所以我们还需要一个默认函数子句
so we also need a default function clause
对于所有其他路径
for all the other paths
因为我们知道这个顺序
and since we know that order
我们需要最后定义的事项
matters we need to define it last
对，我们把它放在这里
right we'll put it right here
重写路径
rewrite path
它只需要我们称之为 con 的任何地图
it's just going to take any map we'll call it co n
因为这是一个单行函数
and since this is a single line function
我们会让它更简洁
we'll make it more concise
原封不动地使用这个平分
using this deuce intact
然后我们只想原封不动地返回那个地图
and then we just want to return that map unchanged
所以这将
so this is going to
匹配路径是野生动物的任何请求
match any requests where the path is wildlife
然后对于
and then for
其他一切都会失败
everything else it's going to fall through
这个函数子句将运行
and this function clause will get run
只是返回对话地图不变
just returning the conversation map unchanged
如果我们保存并运行它
if we give that a save and run it
果然
well sure enough
现在我们所有的要求都是
now all of our requests are
符合我们期望的方式
matching the way we would expect
现在我们可以使用同样的技术来添加一些跟踪
now we can use this same technique to add some tracking
假设每次我们得到一个四四个
let's say every time we get a four or four
让我们记录丢失的路径
let's log the missing path
很好地做到这一点
well to do that
我们只需添加一个函数
we'll just add a function
匹配四个或四个状态码
that matches a four or four status code
然后提取路径
and then extracts the path
现在我们需要等到对话地图
now we'll need to wait until the conversation map
有状态键
has a status key
这发生在路由功能中
and that happens in the route function
所以我们会加入一个新的轨道功能
so we'll slip in a new track function right
在它进入管道之后
after it in the pipeline
然后我们将定义它
and then we'll define it
我们只希望这个函数子句运行
we only want this function clause to run
当状态为四或四时
when the status is a four or four
所以我们将使用模式匹配
so we'll use a pattern match for it
状态需要是四个或四个
status needs to be four or four
然后我们要捕获路径
and then we want to capture the path
我们将在变量调用路径中捕获它
and we'll just capture it in a variable call path
我们会把它分配给 co
and we'll assign that to co
n 所以我们可以在函数体中使用它
n so we can use it in the function body
现在我们可以用这些信息做任何我们想做的事情
now we could do anything we want with this information
但现在让我们打印出警告
but for now let's just print out warning
我们的道路的名字是松散的
the name of our path is on the loose
我们可以在函数体内使用路径，因为
we can use path inside of the function body because
我们在此处的路径上匹配模式
we pattern matched on path here
因为这是一个变量
and because this is a variable
然后它就会被绑定
then it's just going to be bound
到路径中的任何值
to whatever value is in the path
我们需要记住返回对话地图
and we need to remember to return the conversation map
所以它继续流过管道
so it continues flowing through the pipeline
现在我们学习重写功能
now as we learn with the rewrite function
我们还需要定义
we also need to define
匹配所有的默认函数子句
a default function clause that matches all
其他对话地图
the other conversation maps
是的，没错
yeah that's right
所以这个只需要
so this one just takes
对话地图并原样返回
a conversation map and returns it unchanged
如果我们保存并运行它
if we give that a save and run it
如果我们向上滚动到 bigfoot 请求
and if we scroll up to the bigfoot request
好吧，我们看到响应是四或四
well we see the response was a four or four
我们打印出大脚怪逍遥法外
and we printed out that bigfoot is on the loose
所以你可能已经看到了
so you may have seen this coming
但是现在我们知道如何在地图上进行模式匹配
but now that we know how to pattern match on maps
有一种不同的方式来设计我们的路线功能
there's a different way to design our route functions
啊哈
aha
在管线中
in the pipeline
我们目前正在调用这个路由函数
we're currently calling this route function
这需要一个论点
that takes one argument
这张对话地图
this conversation map
然后我们委托
and then we delegate
到接受三个参数的路由函数
to the route function that takes three arguments
然后我们有多个函数子句
and then we have multiple function clauses
该模式匹配两个字符串参数的方法
that pattern match on two string arguments the method
和路径，但我们
and the path but we
现在
now
知道我们可以对其中的内容进行模式匹配
know that we can just pattern match on what's in this
对话地图
conversation map
所以让我们先评论一下
so let's start by commenting this out
因为我们不需要它
because we won't need it
然后我们可以更新它只接受一个参数
and then we can update this to just take one argument
我只是要复制这些
I'm just going to copy these
我们希望这只是采取
we want this just to take a
对话地图，然后我们可以在上面进行模式匹配
conversation map and then we can pattern match on it
所以我们这里有我们的地图
so we'll have our map here
我要把那些粘贴进去
I'm going to paste those in
像那样，然后这将是方法
like that and then this is going to be the method
这就是路径
and this is the path
现在我们需要改变
now we need to change
这些函数子句中的每一个都只是
each of these function clauses to just
采取一个论点
take one argument
这样他们就可以在管道中变冷
so that they can get cold in the pipeline
所以我要这个
so I'll take this one
我把它贴在这里
I'll just paste it down here
这只是熊
and this is just going to be bears
我们拿这个
we take this one
把它贴在这里
paste it down here
这个有点不同，因为我们需要
this one's a bit different because we need to
该参数的模式匹配
pattern match on that parameter
我们可以在这里做
and we can do that right inside of here
使用该二元连接运算符小于
using that binary concatenation operator less than
大于然后我们的 id
greater than and then our id
所以这很整洁
so that's kind of neat
我们可以在里面使用这个匹配
we can use this matching inside
我们在左侧匹配的地图
of a map that we're matching on the left hand side
然后我们在这里捕获所有路线
and then for our catch all route down here
好吧，我们会摆脱这些
well we'll get rid of these
地图看起来像这样
and the map will look like this
我们关心的一切
all we care about
是路径，我们要提取它的值
is the path and we want to extract its value
所以我们就这样重组它
so we'll just restructure it that way
现在所有这些函数子句都只需要一个
and now all of these function clauses take just one
争论对话地图
argument the conversation map
并且管道使用一个参数调用路由
and the pipeline calls route with one argument
所以这些应该可以工作
so these should just work
我们把它存起来
we save that away
果然它像以前一样工作
sure enough it works just as before
与往常一样，有多种方法可以做同样的事情
as always there are multiple ways to do the same thing
这通常只是一个偏好问题
and it's often simply a matter of preference